遗忘天下，个人翻译，如有错误，万望海涵
译制：遗忘天下 后期校订：遗忘天下 上传：遗忘天下
QQ号：529098103 欢迎车迷同学加好友
英文字幕源MemoryOnSmells http://UKsubtitles.ru.
今晚，我吃了一颗大白菜
Tonight, I eat a cabbage,
詹姆斯把一只鸽子扔出了车窗
James throws a bird out of a car
理查德忘记了美国的缩写是什么
and Richard forgets the abbreviation for America.
USB。
USB.
各位小伙伴晚上好！谢谢捧场
Hello, everybody! Good evening.Thank you so much.
谢谢大家。好的
Thank you, everybody. Now,
今天我们先从丹麦说起，因为
I want to start by talking about Denmark because, you see,
这么多年来，这个小小的国家
over the years, this tiny little country has contributed
为世界贡献了太多宝贵东西
so much to the betterment of mankind.
它为我们提供了漂亮的家具，高品质的音响设备
It's given us interesting furniture,stylish hi-fi,
有意思的儿童玩具，当然，还有这个
amusing children's toys and, of course, this.
抹着丹麦黄油的丹麦培根三明治
Danish bacon, Danish butter,wrapped in bread,
这是治疗素食主义者的
to create the only known cure
最好良方
for vegetarianism.
但是丹麦，从未造过一辆汽车...直到今天
Denmark, however,has never made a car... until now.
丹麦的人均风能占有率
Because Denmark has more windmills per head
居世界第一
than any other country on Earth
并且哥本哈根是个自行车天堂
and because Copenhagen is a cyclist's paradise,
所以你很容易猜到他们造出来的车会是啥样
you know exactly what sort of car it's going to be.
没错，好吧，其实不像你想的那样
Yeah, well, it isn't.
我也曾猜测这车会不会像安徒生脸上长着一副雨刷
I was also expecting Hans Christian Andersen with windscreen wipers
或者小美人鱼长着门把手，但我错了
or The Little Mermaid with door handles, but no.
实际上这车是这样的
What we've got instead is this.
一辆1086马力的橙色猛兽！
A 1,086 horsepower orange monster!
它叫Zenvo ST1，速度奇快无比
It's called the Zenvo ST1 and it is extremely fast.
搭载了一台6.8升V8引擎
It's got a 6.8 litre V8
同时还有一对机械加涡轮的双增压系统
which is supercharged AND turbocharged.
这就像哈瓦那辣椒上抹芥末酱
And that's like smearing a habanero chilli with wasabi
再把它们塞进炸药里
and then garnishing it with dynamite.
结果就是这车的速度快得连仪表都跟不上了
The net result is a speedometer that can't keep up.
指针飞转。138英里（222公里）150英里（241公里）
170英里（273公里）还在增长
It's just a blur.138, 150, 170-something
我的天！太快了！
My God! No, no idea!
显然油门见底的速度能达到233英里每小时（374公里）
Apparently, however, flat out,it will do 233mph.
各位知道北欧犯罪悬疑剧里
You know those Scandinavian crime dramas,
那些穿着背带衫倚窗发呆的人吗？
lots of quietly thoughtful people in jumpers looking out of the window?
这车和他们毫无类似。
This is nothing like that.Nothing at all.
这是辆货真价实的超级跑车
So, it is very definitely a supercar.
但因此也引出些问题
And that's a problem
谁会这么说，不，我不想买法拉利
because who's going to say,"No, I don't want a Ferrari
不想买兰博基尼、帕加尼和布加迪
or a Lamborghini or a Pagani or a Bugatti
也不想保时捷、奥迪R8、迈凯轮以及阿斯顿马丁
or a Porsche or an Audi R8 or a McLaren or an Aston Martin
我想买辆出自一家连名字都没听说过的
I would rather spend my money on something totally unproven,
小公司生产的跑车？
preferably from a company I've never heard of?
我意思是，凭啥买它？
I mean, why would you do that?
这车也没有那种天使般的做工
It's not like the engine is made from the tears of an angel
以及天神一样的操控性
by the gods of science and precision.
更何况它的悬挂系统非常传统
What's more,it has conventional suspension
底盘也是死沉的钢制结构
and a heavy, steel chassis.
不过，正是由于这些老气的设计
However, because it's a bit last-week, you can
你能在它身上体验到那种久违的驾驶乐趣
have some old-fashioned fun in the corners.
哦嚯嚯！
Oh-ho-ho!
但有时你也会玩脱手
But you can also have an accident.'
一部分原因是如果你启动运动或者赛道模式
Part of the problem is that if you engage sport or race mode,
牵引力控制系统就会彻底关闭
the traction control is disengaged.
现在，这辆车，按照 - 喔 - 设计它的工程师说法
Now, this, according to the - oops - chief engineer,
变得更难驾驭
makes it pretty much undrivable
他是对的
He's right.
他说的没错
He is right.
这车的可靠性同样值得怀疑
There were also some issues with quality.
车灯内会产生凝结
The lights filled with condensation,
后刹车经常出问题
the rear brakes didn't seem to be working properly,
接着离合器也失效了
then the clutch went.
所以我们只能把车运回丹麦处理
So the car had to go back to Denmark.
几周后，它被修好了
After a couple of weeks,however, it was mended,
所以Zenvo重回赛道
so the Zenvo came back.
但几乎同时...
But almost immediately...
一个散热风扇出了故障
a cooling fan went wrong.
火警，火警，火警！收到
Fire, fire, fire! Copy that.
就这样，这车变得更显火热
So the car became even more orange.
于是，我们的评测也到此为止
And that was the end of that.
不尽如人意
That didn't do very well.
这货卖多少钱？你说价格？嗯.
How much is this thing? How much? Mm.
80万英镑。80万？！（814万人民币）
£800000. 800?!
没错。这玩意有什么优点吗？呃，优点，有
Yes. Are there any upsides to it? Er, upsides, yes.
大火把车灯内的水雾烤干了
The fire did get rid of the condensation in the lights.
除这以外呢？除这以外...
Apart from the fire? Apart from the fire...
还有，它表现的非常舒适安静
Yes, it's surprisingly comfortable and very quiet.
好吧，它都已经挂了，自然很安静
Well, it would be quiet.It was broken.
是的，但神奇的是，厂方又把它修好送了回来
Yes, but amazingly, they have mended it again and it's back again.
现在要看看它在我们赛道表现如何
And now we can find out how fast it does a lap of our track,
或者说它如果能完好的跑完一圈
or rather IF it can do a lap of our track.
也就是说又到了请出我们圈养车手的时刻
That, of course, means handing it over to our tame racing driver
据说这周他穿了两层防火服以备不测
Some say that this week he is wearing two layers of Nomex.
并且在最近一次前往康沃尔的旅途中
And that on a recent trip to Cornwall,
他在萨默塞特郡路边草丛里方便被人发现
he stopped off for one of his special big wees in Somerset.
大家都知道他就是Stig！
All we know is he's called The Stig!
起步！
And he's off!
小心翼翼的起步，因为赛道很湿滑
Cautious start because it is soaking out there today.
着火之后看起来更加艳丽动人。好的，进入第一弯
Be beautiful, though, if it catches fire. Right, first corner.
会出故障吗？目前为止安然无恙
Will it try to bite him? Nothing so far.
噢，不，等等，出弯有点不稳
Oh, no, wait, there is a bit of a nibble at the end.
完全不知道他听的是啥
Absolutely no idea what The Stig is listening to.
但我知道，他开启的是赛道模式。没有牵引力控制
I do know, however, he is in full race mode. No traction control
这个弯很小心
He is being cautious, though.
好的，穿过榔头弯
Right, through the Hammerhead.
噢，不，又有些甩尾，但他控制住了
Oh, no, it's stepped out again,but he has managed to hold it.
天啊，技术真不错！
God, that is very good driving!
好的，他会松油门吗？
Right, is he going to lift?
噢，是的，油门放了一点
Oh, yes, he is going to lift
因为这车就和丹麦首相一样活泼
because that thing is as racy as the Danish Prime Minister.
穿过轮胎墙
Through the tyres.
还剩两个弯
Only two corners left.
你能清楚的看到这车过弯时的摆动
You can actually see it squirming on the lake where our track used to be.
过了最后的Gambon弯就能松口气了。它能完成吗？
Only Gambon left before he can have a lie down. Is he going to make it?
能做到吗？
Is IT going to make it?
是的，它完成了！
Yes, it has!
好的...
Now...
成绩在我这里
I have the time here.
记住，这是辆价值80万英镑，1000马力的跑车，让我们瞧瞧
Remember, it is an £800,000 1,000 horsepower car, so here we go.
哦...
Ohhh...
不，还要低些。是吗？
No, it's a bit lower. Really?
哦...
Ohhh...
噢-不！
Oh-ho!
就是这里，1分29秒9
There you go, it's 1.29.9,
比一辆福克斯还慢
slower than a Ford Focus.
不，不，等等。抱歉，等等
No, no, hang on a minute.I'm sorry. Hang on a minute.
让我们公正点评价它。我们找个另外的湿圈
Let's be fair about it. We need to look at another time for a wet lap.
就是这个。它比一辆德国房车还慢。是的！
There you go. It's slower than a German saloon car. It is!
各位知道这是一辆橙色的丹麦货，并且天生就有个缺陷
You know this is Danish and it s orange and it's genetically flawed
我很惊讶他们没有管它叫长颈鹿...
I'm surprised they haven't called The Giraffe...
并且给它来一枪
（最近日德兰动物园一头名为“马里乌斯”的
长颈鹿死刑问题引起欧洲广泛舆论）
and shot it.
他说的很大声，是吗？他确实这么说了
He said that out loud,didn't he? He did.
他居然说这事
He said it out loud.
假装没听见，让我们进入新闻环节
Never mind,let's move on with the news
好的，我要说的本周新闻，显然
and, well,my big news this week, certainly
就是上周我驾驶了保时捷918
is I spent last weekend driving the new Porsche 918.
噢，你真的做了！以后的节目里我们会放给大家看。就是这货
Oh, you did! It'll be on the show later in the series. There it is.
好的，快点，快点，先给大家说说。这车如何？
Come on, quick, quick, now,sneak preview. What is it like?
好的，詹妮弗...
Well, Jennifer...
有你的！
Funny!
是的，如果各位看了上周的节目，杰瑞米说了
Yeah, if you were watching last week,Jeremy did say on the show,
就在电视上，如果保时捷918比迈凯轮P1快
on TV, that if the Porsche was faster than the McLaren,
他会改名叫詹妮弗。是的
he would change his name to Jennifer.Yes.
对吧，詹妮弗？但是，它做不到。跟你讲，我感觉918是这样的
Didn't you, Jennifer? Well, it won't be. See, I think it might just be.
说实话，这车...快的让人胆颤
Honestly, it... It's staggering Really.
它的加速感不像其它车那样
It doesn't accelerate like most other cars.
你不会觉得它的加速
You are not conscious of it
是伴着转速提升而逐渐提高的
gaining speed through the gear as the revs rise.
它不像这样加速“噢 - 啊！”
It doesn't go, "Ohhh-aaahhh!"
它的速度直接像这样“啊啊啊啊！”
It just goes straight to, "Aaaaargh!"
但是，哈蒙德...什么？
But, Hammond... What?
迈凯轮比保时捷的动力更强
the McLaren has more power than the Porsche
体重更轻。我知道
and is lighter than the Porsche。I know.
但是听着，詹妮弗，保时捷有四轮驱动系统
But listen, Jennifer,the Porsche has four-wheel-drive
以及四轮转向系统，并且在我们赛道上的表现...
and four-wheel steer and on our track...
它会输给迈凯轮
It will lose.
听着，我承认纳粹空军飞行员对他们的
Listen, I'm sure the Luftwaffe were very proud
梅塞施密特109战斗机非常骄傲和自豪
and pleased with the Messerschmitt Me 109.
那是种很优秀的战斗机。是的，但它没有...
That was a damn good aeroplane.Yes, but it wasn't...
它没有喷火式战斗机优秀！
It wasn't as good as the Spitfire!
不，梅塞施密特109能做负过载机动动作
No, you could do negative G in the Messerschmitt 109.
梅，你怎么和他一样讨厌！我会让它会输得很难看
May, you are as bad as he is! That is going to be humiliated.
我们会赢得胜利。我说“我们”，指的是我们英国...
We are going to win. When I say we,Britain is going to...
我们都是爱国人士，那没错
I'm all for patriotism,that's great,
但你必须面对事实。这车很棒
but you've just got to face facts.The thing is astonishing.
它的精髓在于如何控制三台引擎一起...给我闭嘴！
It's about how it manages those three engines... Shut up about it!
我赞同你的爱国情怀
I'm with you about the British thing,
但我同样希望保时捷能赢，詹妮弗
but I sort of hope the Porsche wins, JENNIFER.
不管怎样，最近新闻里充斥着各种洪水之后
Anyway look，The news has been filled with a lot of scenes
灾民冲镜头挥手求援的场面
of flood victims all waving their arms around
“噢，不，我们该怎么办？”
and going, "Oh, no,what are we going to do?"
就像世界末日一样
End of the world really.
这场面让我很失望，因为解决的方法
I mean, it certainly makes me very sad because the answer,
非常简单
as we all know, is simple.
你买辆福特全顺，在地板上挖个大洞
You buy a Ford transit van,cut a big hole in the floor,
卸掉后门，放个引擎进去，加上风扇，裙边
take the back doors off, couple of engines in it, fans, skirts,
然后开到水上，这样它就沉了。没错
put it in the water, it sinks.That's true.
之后你再买辆全顺，弄台更大的引擎
You get another transit van,more powerful engines,
一番大改。就像这样
totally redesigned. Here we go.
表现完美。这就是解决方案
And it works perfectly.That is the solution.
我们六个月前就预测到了这场洪水并且给出了解决方案
We predicted these floods six months ago and came up with the solution.
但令我们失望的是每个人
But what is really annoying is that everybody
都在抱怨戴维·卡梅伦（英国首相），环境署
is blaming the floods on David Cameron, the Environment Agency
以及更多你可以抱怨的对象...
pretty much anything you can name...
恩，我知道谁最应该
Mm-mm, I know exactly who is to blame
对这种情况负责
for this problem everybody is having.
米兰达·哈特（英国演员、作家、喜剧演员）
Miranda Hart.
你们都笑了，但事实是
You laugh, but here's the thing
虽然每周日晚上我们坐这陪着各位
We are sitting here now on a Sunday evening.
可还是有8、9百万英国人选择观看
Eight, nine million people in Britain have chosen to watch
另一个频道的1950年助产教学片
some 1950s midwifery on the other side,
以至于他们从没说过我们的气垫车
so they don't know about the hover-van.
这是个问题
That is the problem.
他们宁愿看米兰达也不看我们的节目，
They have chosen Miranda over us and our show is
即使我们节目充满了各种有用的小贴士和消费建议。每周如此！
rammed full of helpful hints and useful consumer advice. Every week!
换个话题，嘿，盖拉多已经生产多久了
Now, hey, listen, how long has the Gallardo been in production
有17000年历史了吧？有了？有了
17,000 years? Just over? Just over.
我知道它们在史前文明时就已经在产了。是的
I know there are cave drawings of it in the Pyrenees. There are.
如今兰博基尼宣布他们将停产盖拉多
Well, Lamborghini has announced they are stopping making it
并发布全新换代车型。它叫“胡拉坎”（飓风）
and are going to replace it with this. It's called the Huracan.
600马力，5.2升排量V10引擎，四轮驱动
600 horsepower, 5.2 litre V10,four-wheel-drive.
没任何新鲜玩意
None of that is interesting
因为如果你痴迷于速度、马力、操控感
because if you're interested in speed and power and handling,
你会选择法拉利458或者迈凯轮12C，对吧？
you're going to buy a Ferrari 458 or a McLaren 12C, aren't you?
而选择兰博基尼的唯一理由是它们看起来很疯狂
The only reason you want to buy a Lamborghini is because it looks mad.
虽然这车看起来疯狂，但我认为它疯狂的还不够
And that's very nice, but I don t think it's bonkers enough.
我明白你的意思。它看起来很漂亮，但是...
I know what you mean.It looks nice, but...
是的，它还要长得更疯狂。是的
Yeah, it needs to be outrageous.It does.
如果一个人没喝下两大瓶苦艾酒
Nobody should be allowed to design a Lamborghini
他就没资格担任兰博基尼设计师
unless they've just consumed two bottles of absinthe.
像这样！
Now you're ready!
这里面的精髓是
The essence of it is,
一辆兰博基尼不在于它的驾驶感如何
it doesn't really matter how a Lamborghini drives
因为兰博基尼是用来在城市里招摇过市的
because a Lamborghini is for prowling around the city
法拉利是用来在银石赛道刷圈速的
Ferraris are for doing a 2.35 around Silverstone.
兰博基尼适合徘徊于凌晨2点35的骑士桥附近
（骑士桥：伦敦市中心西部繁华商业街）
Lamborghinis are for doing Knightsbridge at 2.35am.
是的，是的
Yes, yes.
最近，政府正为一种新的气体头疼
Now, there's a new type of gas which is worrying the government.
是氰化物？不。二氧化碳吗？
Is it cyanide? No.Is it carbon dioxide?
不，曾经是二氧化碳。怎么说呢
No, it used to be carbon dioxide.Now the days where
我都难以启齿
I can hardly bring myself to say this.
他们担心的是氮氧混合气
They are very worried about a terrifying new combination of nitrogen and oxygen.
什么，你是说空气？是的
What, you mean air? Yes.
空气99%成分是由这两种气体构成
99% of the air that we breathe is nitrogen and oxygen,
但政府有关部门现在为这点破事瞎操心
but the government has got his knickers in a twist about it,
尤其是氮氧化物，我事先补了点化学知识
specifically about nitrogen dioxide and I've done some checking.
抱歉
Bear with me on this.
它们大多来自土壤、锅炉
It mostly comes from soil or stoves
以及柴油车在市中心行驶的工况排放，知道吗？
or particularly from lorries in stop-start city driving, OK?
所以政府决定解决这个问题
So the government has decided to address the problem
他们把谢菲尔德市旁的M1公路限速降到60英里
(英格兰南约克郡城市)
by limiting cars to 60mph on the M1 just outside Sheffield.
这就是他们的解决办法。但这和减排毫无关系！
That's their solution.But that's got nothing to do with it!
就像说“我牙痛
Isn't that like saying,"I've got toothache,
我要去理个发，那样牙就不痛了”
I think I'll go and have a hair cut. That will sort it."
大夫，我扭伤了脚。你得穿上件小马甲
Doctor, I've twisted my ankle."You must put on a bomber jacket"
实际上，有关部门表示“这是整个欧洲的法规，
The thing is, they actually say "Well, it's as European law,
所以我们必须限速”
so we have to lower the speed limit."
德国不这么干，法国不这么干，
意大利也不这么干，只有英国这么做
Germans aren't, French aren't,Italians aren't, only we are.
我知道究竟怎么回事了
And I know exactly what's happened here.
政府里有些这样的人，你懂的...
You've got some guy in the government, you know...
你知道那种类型。噢，是的，没错
You know the type. Oh, yes, right.
OK，现在，他有权利降低限速
OK, now, he has the power to lower the speed limit
禁止车内有儿童时父母不准吃三明治
and stop parents eating sandwiches in cars if kids are present,
但他真需要做的事情是行使女王的权利
but what he needs to do is take a leaf out of the Queen's book.
什么，嫁给希腊人？不！
What, marry a Greek? No!
宪法赋予女王
The Queen has the constitutional power
对他国宣战的权利
to declare war on another country,
但她从没用过
but she never does.
甚至一场派对结束之后她有点...
Even after a big party where she's a bit...
所有伙伴都怂恿她
and all her mates are egging her on.
上啊，莉兹！去宣战！她真会那么做吗？
Go on, Liz! Declare war on someone!" Can she really do that?
是啊，她有权利那么干，但从未做过。
“哈罗，是奥朗德（法国总统）阁下吗？
Yes, she can do that, but she doesn't. "Hello is that Mr Hollande?
我是英国女王。我们正处于战争时期！”
我每周都这么干！
"This is the Queen. WE ARE AT WAR!"I'd do that every week!
她能这么干。我都会这么干...我会每天都...
She could do that. I'd be constant... I'd do it every...
噢，天啊，我都干了些什么？
Oh, God, what have I done?"
没错，我想成为喝醉酒的女王！
Yeah, I would love to be a drunk Queen!
我意思是...
I didn't mean...
继续下个话题好吗？好的。好的
Shall we move it on? Yes. Yes.
每周，我们都收到数千封观众来信
Every week, we receive thousands of letters from people that say
他们说“亲爱的TopGear节目组，为什么你们从不测试些
Dear Top so-called Gear,why do you never test the sort of
普通人买得起的车呢？”
affordable cars that normal people are likely to buy and drive?"
好吧，实际上，我们想这么做。但制片人不让
Well, the truth is, we would love to. But the producers won't let us.
让人挺遗憾，因为和大多数人一样
It's frustrating,because contrary to public opinion,
我们很喜欢小巧、方便的小型车
we really do like small,sensible little cars.
他家有一辆菲亚特熊猫。我家有一辆菲亚特500
I mean, he has a Fiat Panda.I have a Fiat 500.
是的，我则有一辆小巧的梅赛德斯AMG
Yeah, and I have a very small AMG Mercedes.
已经很小了
Very small indeed.
我们喜欢小车的易于泊车，使用成本低廉
We like the way that small cars are easy to park and cheap to run,
但最重要的是，我们都喜欢
but, most of all,we like the way that a lot of them
它们的驾驶乐趣
are very good fun to drive.
但制片人却不这么认为，他们说这些车都很无趣
But the producers say they aren t,they say they're boring.
为了证明这点，他们发起了一次挑战
And to prove their point,they came up with a challenge.
是的，他们让我们挑选三辆1升排量，三缸引擎
Yes, they told us to choose three one-litre, three-cylinder,
小型家用车去克里米亚半岛接受挑战
little city cars and report with them to the Crimean peninsula.
所以、就是这里，乌克兰南部
So, here it is,at the bottom end of Ukraine,
伸进黑海的这片土地
jutting out into the Black Sea.
克里米亚半岛，
一万平方英里（25888平方公里）历史热土，充满了甜菜根
The Crimean peninsula, 10,000 square miles of history, beetroot
以及各种完爆西方女孩的漂亮妹纸们
and girls who leave the West behind.
这里就是我们集合的地点，雅尔塔
And this is where we were to meet,the city of Yalta.
希特勒战败后，就在这幢建筑物外
Outside the very building where Churchill, Stalin
丘吉尔，斯大林和罗斯福共同瓜分了欧洲大陆
and Roosevelt met to carve up Europe after Hitler's defeat.
哈蒙德第一个抵达
Hammond was the first to arrive
如各位所见，我选了一辆福特嘉年华
I have brought,as you can see, a Fiesta.
一辆在任何方面都很优秀的小车
Which is a very, very good small car in any case,
尤其在此时，它显得更加优秀
but in this instance,particularly good,
因为它搭载了一台精致至极的引擎
because this one is fitted with an absolute jewel of an engine.
这台引擎十分小巧，1升，3缸，带涡轮缸内直喷技术
It's a tiny, one-litre,three-cylinder EcoBoost,
注意我的措辞，我意思是它十分小巧
and when I say tiny,I mean REALLY tiny.
整部引擎的面积可以用一张A4纸完全覆盖
The block of that engine would fit on an A4 piece of paper.
让人惊叹.好了，那是谁？
And it's magnificent.Right, who's that?
噢，是那个猩猩。没错
Oh, it's the orang-utan. Here we go.
恭喜。什么，恭喜啥？
Congratulations. What, why?
因为你这辆车是所有1升车里最棒的一辆
Because that is unquestionably the best one-litre little car of them all.
毫无疑问。它的引擎是...是的
No doubt about it.The engine in this... Yeah.
让人赞叹。125马力，仅仅1升排量.我知道！
It is phenomenal. 125 horsepower,from one litre. I know!
每加仑油能跑65英里（百公里3.6升）。真的是...
And 65 miles to the gallon.Honestly...
为啥老是说我的车，又为啥你不选这辆车呢？
Why are you saying these things and why, then, are you not in one?
为什么你选了那辆大众？这是辆大众Up！
Why are you in that VW? It's the Up!
我选这辆车因为我喜欢它。等等，你的逻辑有点...
Well, I brought this because I like it. Hang on, you've just ..
不，我喜欢这车。虽然你的车很棒。但我喜欢这辆
No, I like it. This is brilliant.But I like this.
让我这么给你解释，哈蒙德
Let me put it to you this way，Hammond
你能买只比我的西高地白梗
（宠物犬种，原产苏格兰）更好的宠物狗
You can buy better dogs than my West Highland terrier,
但我喜欢自己的狗
but I LIKE my West Highland terrier.
没错，它会咬人，在家里到处埋地雷
Yes, it bites the postman and it lays dog eggs all over
还经常偷吃食物，但它们很有爱！它们会这样...
the kitchen and it steals food but it's brilliant! And it goes ..
如果这车也有耳朵，它就会像这样...
If this had ears,it would go like that...
可惜，就在我兴致勃勃的扮演宠物狗时
Sadly, at this point,my dog impersonation was
船长大人姗姗来迟
interrupted by the arrival of Captain Interesting.'
这是我见过最无趣的车...这是辆什么车？看得我都快睡着了！
That's the most boring looking car I've... What is it? I'm nodding off!
好消息！什么？这是辆达契亚Sandero。是嘛？是的
Good news! What? It's a Dacia Sandero. Is it? Yes.
不论如何，你来之前我们讨论好久了
Anyway, we were just saying before you got here,
这是辆很棒的小车
this is just an epic little car
它很贵吧，对吗？它卖多少钱？17500英镑（177500人民币）
It's quite expensive, though,isn't it? How much is it? 17,500.
17500英镑？是的。你的车多少钱？7500英镑（76128人民币）
£17,500? Yup.And how much is yours? 7,500.
真是价格的鸿沟啊，哈蒙德。是的...
That's a big price gulf,Hammond. It is...
我能再去买一辆
I can afford to lose this and just go and buy another one
并且钱包仍有余钱。看看它！真是...它看上去很好
and I'm still better off than you.Look at it! It's... It looks great.
这车很低调，它是为那些精打细算的人打造的
It's anti-fashion, it's a car for people with more sense than money.
它使用正常，价格合理。哇奥，他们怎么把车做的这么便宜？
It works, it's cheap. Wow,how have they done it so cheaply?
你都想象不到，不是吗？显然一点...真是奇葩！
You can't work it out, can you? There is no obvious... It's amazing!
瞧这方向盘，糟糕的装配工艺！
That steering wheel,what a quality item!
和你的车没区别！完全不一样！形状类似
That's exactly the same as yours! It isn't the same! It's the same SHAPE.
如果我说的不对请纠正我，这货其实是30年前的雷诺克里奥
And correct me if I'm wrong,it was a Renault Clio 30 years ago.
不是30年前
Not 30 years ago.
它只是以老款雷诺克里奥为基础而已
It's BASED on the underpinnings and mechanicals of the old Renault Clio.
一辆旧车。事实上，我买的是一个拥有iPod外观的老式留声机
An old car. Basically, I've brought an iPod to a gramophone convention.
战五渣！瞧瞧它！
Utter rubbish! Look at it!
我们的讨论被随之而来的挑战暂时打断
Our argument was then interrupted by the arrival of a challenge.
他们仍旧不相信我们喜欢小型车。但事实如此！
They still don't believe that we like small cars. But we do!
我喜欢嘉年华。好的
I love my Fiesta. Right.
在雅尔塔和塞瓦斯托波尔之间，有条极好的滨海公路
Between Yalta and Sevastopol,there is an excellent coast road,
如果驾驶普通车辆，你们会非常享受它
which you would enjoy very much in a normal car.
但现在你们驾驶着三辆悲催的购物车
"But you will not be able to enjoy it
你们不会得到任何乐趣
"in your miserable little shopping carts"?!
喂！
Hello!
你不能忽视这一点，嘉年华在任何方面
You can't get away from the fact the Fiesta, in any guise,
都是辆出色的车
is a brilliant little car.
底盘是如此优秀！
The chassis is so sorted out!
我曾驾驶过ST版本，最运动的那款，那车真是棒极了
I've driven the ST version,the hot one, and it is simply superb.
令人惊讶的是在这台小引擎的驱动下
What's incredible is that they haven't lost any of that liveliness,
这车没有失去任何活泼、刺激、敏捷的特性，
that excitement, that thrill, by fitting it with a tiny, tiny engine.
就像在动画片里开车似的！
It's like driving a cartoon!
不错！
Squealing!
一点点涡轮，一点点牵引力控制
Bit of turbo boost,bit of traction control wise.
我正在这车的物理极限游走
That means I'm having fun and I'm on the ragged edge.
嘿嘿！
Hee-hee!
不像福特和达契亚，Up！没有涡轮
Unlike the Ford and the Dacia,the Up! doesn't have a turbocharger.
但即使这样，它开起来依旧很刺激
But even so, it still feels like a determined spur.
我要拿第一！是的，我会的，给我闪开！
I'm going to get there first!Yes, I am, get out of my way!
唔-哈-哈！
Woo-ha-ha!
把它开进弯道...
And stick it into the bend...
我想说，如果我开的是辆法拉利，我会想
I mean, if I were in even a Ferrari on this road, I'd be thinking
噢，不，我可能会刮花保险杠！
Oh, no, I'm going to scrape my nose!
这里需要多少油门和多大力度的刹车？
但现在我不需要担心这些
"How much power do I need here and how much braking?" And I don't
因为Up！的引擎非常肉
have to worry about any of that,because the Up! has no power at all.
你只需要把油门踩到底并且保持住就行了！
You just put your foot hard down and leave it there!
让制片人很不开心的是
Much to the annoyance of the producers,
我们很享受一路上的驾驶乐趣
we have loved our drive on the wiggly road.
但令我们更兴奋的是路的尽头我们发现了新玩意
But we loved what we found at the other end of it even more.
一个废弃的前苏联潜艇基地
A disused Soviet submarine base
通常情况下，我们会把车停到停车场去
Now, ordinarily, we would have to park in the car park there.
但我们的车都很小，所以这次不用
But because our cars are so little,we won't.
真是太震撼了
This is remarkable.
詹姆斯·邦德都没能进来过这里！
James Bond could not have got in here!
显然，他的阿斯顿马丁太宽了
Because of course,his Aston Martin is too large.
老天！
Good God!
瞧瞧！
Look at that!
万一发生核战争
In the event of a nuclear war,
这里能容纳14艘潜艇，以及3000名士兵
they could get 14 submarines in here, and 3,000 people.
整个基地藏在山里！
It's under a mountain!
是的，现在这里就是我们的潜艇基地
Yeah, it is your actual under-a-mountain submarine base
我们三就是007
It's full-on Bond.
想当年，军情六处和中央情报局要费多少
How much energy and effort was expended by MI6
人力财力才能找到并弄清这里的每个细节？
and the CIA trying to find out the details of this place?
而现在我，却驾车穿梭其中！
And here I am, driving through it!
可惜，我们在潜艇基地逛了太久...
Sadly, we spent so long driving around the sub pen...
当我们赶到塞瓦斯托波尔时
that night was falling by the time we reached
天色已晚
the busy city of Sevastopol.
在这里，Up！孱弱的动力让我备受欺凌
And here, the Up!'s lack of oomph was a bit of an issue.
噢，我被加塞了！
Oh, I'm being squeezed!
我输了。我被一辆拉达2107给超掉了！
I've lost it.Being strashed by a Lada 2107!
但是，也正由于大众小巧的体积
However, because the VW is smaller than the Ford
我不需要把车停到距离酒店千里之外的停车场
and the Dacia, I didn't have to park miles and miles from the hotel.
停这合法吗？不，这里写了禁止停车吗？
Is that legal? No.Where does it say "no parking"?
但很多不适合停车的地方
But it doesn't say "no parking"in a lot of places where it's
也没标明“禁止停车”
obviously not quite right to park.
要这么说，这里也没写“禁止谋杀”
To be fair,it doesn't say "no murdering" either.
第二天早上，我们驾车穿越了一片
The next morning,we continued our journey through
英国人曾为之浴血奋战的土地
a region where the hills were once soaked with British blood.
克里米亚战争至今让人捉摸不透
The Crimean War may have been unfathomable,
没人真正了解它为什么爆发，但它给人类留下了非常多遗产
nobody really knew why it started,but the legacy is enormous.
它让我们知道了巴拉克拉法帽（也叫做滑雪头罩）和羊毛衫
It gave us important words like balaclava and cardigan.
留给人类伟大的弗洛伦斯·南丁格尔
It gave us Florence Nightingale
出现了世界第一位战地摄影师，第一位战地记者
the world's first war photographer,the world's first war reporter.
第一枚维多利亚十字勋章授予了这场战争中表现杰出的士兵
The Victoria Cross was first awarded to soldiers who fought here
直到今天，这种勋章的制造原料
And even today,the medal is made from metal
都取自那次战争中在这里缴获的俄军武器
taken from a Russian gun that was captured here.
之后，就诞生了那首流传已久的著名诗歌
Then, of course, there's the best-known legacy of them all.
那诗怎么写的？
How's it go?
“无人答复，没有缘由
"Theirs not to make reply,Theirs not to reason why,
有的只是去战斗去迎接死亡
"Theirs but to do and die."
进入死亡之谷，战死骑兵600名”
（出自丁尼生诗作《轻骑兵的冲锋》）
那就是诗中描述的山谷
"Into the valley of death，rode the 600." And that is the valley.
那就是诗里轻骑兵被屠杀的地方
That is where the Charge of the Light Brigade actually happened
那是条被曲解的命令
（克里米亚战争巴拉克拉瓦战役中，
由于通讯人员错误传达命令导致数百英军骑兵阵亡）
It was a misunderstood order.
是的，他们本应该去到那里
Yeah, they were supposed to go up there somewhere.
他们本应爬上那座山丘，寻找俄军
They were supposed to snout around in the hills, looking for the Russians,
军令被曲解，他们被要求攻占那里，并且只配备了马刀，
去冲击全副武装的俄军炮兵部队
misunderstood it, came charging over here armed with sabres,
against the entire Russian artillery here
就发生在那边，径直的冲向俄军
all of it was there,pointing straight at them.
只有战马和马刀
And they were on horses with sabres.
怎么会发生这种悲剧？
How could that possibly end?
噢，上帝！
Oh, God!
时机掌握得真好！是的。太准了
Choose your moments!Exactly. Exactly.
乌克兰是全欧洲第二大国家，现在你们要
"Ukraine is the second largest country in Europe, and now you will
驾车穿越它
"drive all the way across it,
从最南边的这里直到和白俄罗斯边境接壤的北部
"from here in the far south to the Belarus border in the north
这段旅程会比你们小时候坐车去海边渡假
"It will be worse than those long journeys you did
的那种体验更加糟糕
"as a kid in the back of a family car to the seaside.
这将是段地狱般的旅程
"It will be the journey from hell."
怎么可能比小时候更糟？那时我还是个孩子！
How can it be worse than those journeys? I was a kid then!
我那时坐的是一辆莲花Cortina Mk 1
I was in the back of a Mark I Cortina.
我小时候坐的是奥斯汀1100
I was in the back of an Austin 1100.
我是安格利亚。这段路多长？车底还破个洞。
Anglia。How far is it?with a hole in the floor。
这段路多长？总共750英里（1207公里）
How far is it?It's 750 miles.
750英里？用一辆大众Up！？太容易了。小菜一碟...
750 miles? What, in a Volkswagen Up!? That's easy. Piece of ca..
用这三辆小车，很轻的小车
In these three cars，light cars
我们就像现代版的轻骑兵旅
we shall be the modern-day Charge of the Light Brigade.
没错
Very good.
带着些许伤感，我们出发了
Still feeling slightly baffled,we set off.
我觉得制片人变的有些温柔了，说实话
Well, I think the producers have gone a bit soft, to be honest.
这次挑战一点难度都没有...这种程度...
It's just not in any way difficult,challenging... It's just...
太简单了！
It's easy!
750英里！
750 miles!
后来证明这次挑战一点不简单
It turned out not to be easy at all.
是的，后面的内容
Yes, in the second part of that film,
等会再放，我几乎挂掉了
which we'll show you later on,I was actually killed.
是的，确实如此
Yeah, he really was.
这正是我们期待已久的结果
So, that's something for us all to look forward to.
好吧，谢你全家，哈蒙德
Yes, thank you, Hammond.
但现在，又到了嘉宾做客环节
But in the meantime, we must put a Star in our Reasonably Priced Car.
今晚我的嘉宾是英国音乐人里唯一一个
Now, my guest tonight is the only British musician who can
既开过坦克，又玩过迫击炮，还能耍枪的奇才
drive a tank, fire a mortar and strip an assault rifle.
当然，我说的不是辣妹
（维多利亚·卡洛琳·贝克汉姆，小贝老婆）
Apart from Posh Spice, obviously.
女士们先生们，詹姆仕·布朗特！（英国流行歌手）
Ladies and gentlemen, James Blunt!
你好，伙计。你好，很好
How you doing, big man。How are you? I'm well.
大家好。各位好。嗨，大家好。请坐
Hi there. How are you doing? Hi Hello. He's here. Have a seat.
好的。好多口哨声！
All right. Many whistlings!
首先，恭喜你就要结婚了
First of all, congratulations on your forthcoming marriage.
我要结婚了？（屏蔽声）
I'm getting married?（BLEEP!）
你就要和你身后的那位女孩结婚了。不错
You're getting married to the girl standing behind you. Fantastic
只是以防你忘记了。不，不是那位，看
Just in case you'd forgotten.No, there she is, look.
你叫啥名字？啊！
What's your name? Aah!
那才是正主。OK，不错。说真的，啥时候结婚？
That's the ticket. OK, great.So, when are you getting married?
9月
September.
我刚才在想，我知道这里很多女孩都想让我
I'm just thinking, I know there s lots of girls here and they'll
问你这方面的问题，但我想不出问什么
want me to ask lots of questions about it, but I can't think of any.
我们说说军队吧？好的就说军队
Shall we talk about the Army? Let's talk about the Army.
部队的故事不错。简单易懂
The Army's better. We've got to do the Army, it's easier.
我们都知道你曾在部队服役，流传甚广
Now, we know you were in the Army,of course, that is well documented.
但我想很多人不知道的是
But I think what a lot of people don't know is that you actually
你曾在科索沃独自一人
single-handedly,when you were in Kosovo,
阻止了第三次世界大战的爆发
stopped World War III from happening.
很高兴你能提及此事。是的，是该让英国人民知道这件事了
I'm glad you brought this up. Yeah.Because it's time the nation knew.
事实上，那是我这辈子最传奇的一天
Actually, it was genuinely the most incredible day of my life.
仅次于即将到来的婚礼
Other than my forthcoming marriage.
呃...是的...
And, er... It was...
你知道，把塞尔维亚人轰炸撤退后
You know, having bombed the crap out of the Serbs,
我们签署了一份和平协议并且推进到普里什蒂纳
we signed a peace accord and we pushed up to Pristina,
科索沃的首都，我被提拔成一名带领
the capital, and I was remarkably put as truly the first officer
30000人的军官
to lead 30,000 people up there,
当我们抵达普里什蒂纳机场时，克拉克将军
and when we got to the airport in Pristina, General Wesley Clark
命令我们彻底消灭
told us to just overrun
200名曾经打败过我们的俄国守军
and overpower the 200 Russians who had beaten us to the airport
那个美国将军？
The American general?
是的，我们曾几次提出质疑，
那条命令是不是要我们彻底消灭俄国士兵？
Yeah, and we asked several times，that one thing means destroy them?
现在看来是条非常愚蠢的命令。他说彻底消灭...
Which seemed a pretty stupid thing to do. He said destroy...
他要求彻底消灭，清楚的使用了一些政治上的措辞
He said overrun and overpower,
definitely using some political manoeuvring in his wording.
经过五分钟的争论
And after, you know,five minutes of arguing,
麦克·杰克逊将军
a very special man called General Mike Jackson,
一个我很敬仰的人
an incredible character who I would follow anywhere,
从无线电里传来他的声音
came up on the radio and said,
“简直荒谬绝伦，我不会让我的士兵
"This is ridiculous,I'm not having my soldiers being
背上引发第三次世界大战的罪名
responsible for starting World War III,
让部队离开那里”
let's push off somewhere else.
当俄守军的食物消耗完后
And when the Russians had run out of food and water,
他们向我们寻求帮助，我们就对他们说
“没问题，只要你们开放机场就行”
they came back and asked us for food and water and we said,
"Sure, if you share the airport"
那是一位美军将军向英军上尉发布命令...
That was an order from an American to a British captain to...
那以后他就竞选美国总统去了（小布什竞选对手）。我知道
And he later then ran for president in America. I know
让我们聊聊音乐。军队已经聊很多了
Let's move on to music.We've covered the army.
你阻止了三战爆发拯救了世界，这很好
You saved the world from World War III, which is good.
你的新专辑叫登陆月球
Your new album is called Moon Landing.
登陆月球，我第一次发现它的真实含义
Moon Landing, which I only discovered after the event
是在一本都市辞典上
that "moon landing" is actually in the Urban Dictionary
他的真意是：健身房里两个男人同时弯腰时
as a term in the gym when two men are changing and they bend over
两人的屁股碰巧撞到了一起。所以，是的...
and their bottoms touch accidentally.So, yeah...
专辑里有支单曲叫心连心，对吗？是的
There's a single called Heart To Heart, isn't there? Yes.
请允许我帮闺女问你个问题
Now, forgive me for saying this my daughter,
几天前她对我说“我要在推特上向詹姆士
she said to me a couple of days ago,"I was going to tweet James
表达我有多喜欢那首歌”但她说“我很怕
"to say how much I love that song,"but she said, "I was so worried
他对我的回复很恶劣，所以我一直没敢这么做”
"that his tweet reply would rip me apart that I haven't dared do it."
我不会朝她恶语相向，如果她没啥恶意
I wouldn't abuse her,if she's nice.
你最近在推特上得了个什么头衔？
What have you just won on Twitter?
叫什么，推特最佳...最佳留言回复者
It's something, the best twitterer... Best Comebacks.
最佳留言回复者，那边梳着吹风头的帅哥说的不错
The Best Comebacks, from the chap over there with windswept hair
我这里摘录了几条你的留言
I've actually got a few of your ones here.
你是花了很长时间去琢磨这些回复么？
Don't they take a long time to think of?
我会说都是无意的，但恐怕这是在撒谎
I would say I'm spontaneous with it,but I might be lying.
有人这么给你留言“你为什么只有20万粉丝？”
Somebody said here, "Why have you only got 200,000 followers?"
你回答他“耶稣也只有12个门徒而已”
And you replied,"Jesus only needed 12."
得承认...这些回复很有趣
You've got to admit...they are properly very funny.
“ 詹姆仕·布朗特长着一张讨厌的脸和一副破锣嗓子”
"James Blunt has an annoying face and a highly irritating voice.
你回复道“是啊，但是没有按揭款”
You went, "Yes, and no mortgage"
介意我放一张我最喜欢的回复吗？随意
Do you mind if I show them my absolute favourite? Go for it.
最挖苦人的一条“ 詹姆仕·布朗特究竟出了什么事？”
The rather sarky,"Whatever happened to James Blunt?"
这就是答复他的图片
And this was the picture you posted.
我喜欢你的地方在于，对于那些攻击你的言论
What I love about you is the way that somebody is abusive to you
你总是淡然处之，回复的十分有趣。看的我都乐趴了
and you just take it on the chin and are fine. I sob uncontrollably.
我想说，人们对待推特过于认真了
I mean, people take Twitter far too seriously.
推特只是个网络世界而已
It's just,there's a real world out there,
大部分人觉得它很重要
and people seem to think that Twitter is important.
这是人们错误的观点，这种观点很二
It's just people opinions,and opinions are like arseholes
每个人都会犯二。是的，说说车
Everyone has one. Yeah. Cars.
记得你上次做客本节目时
When you were last here, I think
那时你唯一开过的车是拉达
the only car you'd ever driven at the time was a Lada.
没错，那时真的非常尴尬，我试着去升级它
Yeah, I was really embarrassed about that, and I've tried to upgrade.
我曾开的是一辆拉达丽娃1.3SL，SL代表“龟速”
I had a Lada Riva 1.3SL, for "slow".
如今，显然情况改变了很多
Because now, obviously,things have moved on dramatically.
你有了一辆嘟嘟车
You've got a tuk-tuk.
我从曼谷买了一辆嘟嘟车，太棒了，一种三轮车
I have a tuk-tuk from Bangkok,which is awesome, three-wheeled
能跑到70英里每小时（112公里），
我在位于伊比沙岛的家里驾驶它
vehicle, does 70mph, and I drive it around home in Ibiza.
它能跑到70英里？
It does 70?
70英里，如果你能带着你的朋友坐在后座
70mph, and if you get all your mates in the back,
你能稳稳的开到70英里
you can wheelie as well, at 70mph.
事实上，我有个叫Nin的好朋友，是个印度人
Actually, my best friend is a chap called Nin, he's Indian,
他一直坚持驾驶那辆嘟嘟车，
并且假装很轻松的开到70迈
and he insists on driving to make it look more authentic.
没错
Yeah.
当你住在伦敦，我猜你骑自行车。没错
When you're in London, I gather you've now got a bicycle. Yeah.
为什么骑自行车？骑车更快捷，并且锻炼身体
Why do you have a bicycle? It's much,much faster and it's good exercise.
你能减掉小肚子
You can lose a paunch with a bicycle.
我买了辆自行车，看看我的效果。显而易见
I've got a bicycle, and look what it's done to me. Literally.
你不应该把它吃掉的
You're not supposed to eat it.
是啊...
Yeah...
最近，有关你和狗仔的新闻炒得火热
Now, you recently had an altercation with a paparazzi photographer,
是在美国发生的，对吧
I believe, in the United States
是的，狗仔很具侵略性
Yeah, paps are quite aggressive and yes,
那次我和朋友从一个聚会出来
I was coming out of a party and I was with someone who
当我出现在大街上时，他们就对着我一顿猛拍。
was in the public eye as well,and they shout. Paps don't want
狗仔不只希望拍到普通照片，他们想拍有料的内容
an ordinary picture,they want an aggressive picture
于是都围着敲打我的车窗
and they're all banging on the window,
其中一个摔倒在我车前，换作你该怎么做？
and one of them fell in front of the car, and what are you supposed to do?
他跌倒在我车前，我不想暗示自己有这种想法
He's fallen down and I wouldn't want to incriminate myself by saying
其实我没有瞄准他轻踩油门驾车慢慢压过了他
that I hadn't spotted him and touched the throttle and went gently over.
这是个错误的做法。但...但我真的这么干了
That would be the wrong thing to do.But... But we did go over him
你感到车身压过了什么肉肉的东西了吗？是的
Did you actually feel the dum-dum? Yes.
一种奇特但令人愉悦的感觉
Something strangely satisfying about it.
与此同时，警察和救护车都赶到了现场
And in the meantime, the police and the ambulance did arrive,
但在警车到来之前，他拍了很多照片
but before they arrived, he got up and took pictures of more people
甚至其他狗仔还拍了几段他碰瓷的片段
They even had some film footage from another paparazzi of him
他一边揉自己的腿一边说“弄的更红，弄得再红一些”
rubbing his leg, saying,"Make it redder, make it redder,
当警察赶到，他对警官说“瞧我，我被他开车压了过去”
and when the police arrived, he said,"Poor me, I've been run over.
但那只是一辆小出租车而已，我想没什么大不了的
But it was a very small hire car and I think it was fine.
不是那种大凯迪拉克？不是。下次你再弄一辆回家
It wasn't a large American Cadillac? No. Get one of those next time.
不管怎样，你的圈速，跑圈那天怎么样？
Anyway, the lap,how was it out there today?
当我今天做圈速时，他们告诉我今天是
I think as I was driving down today,they said today was the first
气象局今年第一次发布红色天气警告
day of the year the Met Office has issued a red weather warning
如没有特殊需要不要离开家门
do not leave home unless you specifically have to,
而我却在赛道上刷圈速
and I've been doing laps.
如各位所知，每个来这开车的嘉宾
The thing is, as you know,everybody who comes down here
都会在倒数第二弯冲出赛道，这是正常的，没错
goes off at the second to last corner, that's a given, really,
但我听说詹姆仕从始自终一直冲出赛道
but I heard that James went off on the Follow Through.
但我也坚持到了时间用尽！
And I followed through at the time as well!
这就是为什么叫坚持到底的原因
That's why it's called the Follow Through,
那是个100英里全油门通过的弯道
because that's a 100mph corner,
你对面有个提醒你的工作人员，
and you have that building in front of you, and if things start to
当你即将失控时，他会给你警告提醒...
go wrong through there, it's actually a slightly buttock-clenching...
是的。你们的摄像师很幸运逃过一劫。没错
Very much. And some of your camera crew are lucky to be alive. Yeah
有谁想看看我们的嘉宾在那冲出去的样子吗？
Would anybody like to see this moment when one of our guests
观众：是的
AUDIENCE: Yes.
让我们上眼瞧瞧。放片段
Let's have a look at this.Here we go.
真是倾盆大雨
That is absolutely soaking.
车速确实很快，你把油门踩得死死的直到，看！
That's properly fast, and you keep your foot in it until, look at this!
我很欣赏这段的原因是
What I love about that is you did not apply the brakes
直到距草地一英寸时你才踩下刹车
until you were an inch from the edge of the track.
所有人都说那里不需要松油门，所以我就尝试不松油
Everyone says you're not allowed to lift off and so I tried not to.
你胆子真大
We're talking big cojones there
确实这样，因为当时眼前一片模糊，我什么都看不见
It's actually because I couldn't see through the windscreen.
我都没意识到自己冲了出去
I didn't know I was coming off.
直到车身颠簸眼前一片绿 - “好像冲出赛道了”
It started to get bumpy and green - "This has definitely gone wrong."
不管怎样，最终，我们还是跑完了一圈。
是的，谁想看看？
Anyway, eventually, we did get a lap together. Yeah. Who'd like to see it?
是的！播放正片
Yeah! Here we go.
瞧，我认为这是一次信心十足的起步
See, I think this is the Blitz spirit.
加油！（和谐音）
Come on, then! BLEEP!
赛道就像（和谐音）湖一样
It's like a BLEEP lake out here
是的，没人抱怨环境署
Yeah, nobody's complaining about the Environment Agency,
你进弯了，“你们为什么不把那清理干净？”
you're going in there, "Why don t you come and clear it up?"
真的很湿滑啊！
That is so wet!
路线保持得很好
Stayed on the track nicely.
就像在滑冰
It's like ice skating.
不像我平时那种滑冰
Not that I ice skate very often
你真的需要理查德·哈蒙德的那种座椅增高垫
You really should have borrowed Richard Hammond's booster cushion.
我需要摩西把这里的积水清干净。
（摩西：旧约圣经中分开红海海水的先知）
那有架飞机
I needed Moses to part the sea.There's a private jet over there
它能载我回家！伊比沙岛，没错
That could get me home! Ibiza, right.
榔头弯，可能看不见白线
Hammerhead, probably couldn't even see the lines,
技术不错
so that's pretty impressive.
好的，来到高速弯。太慢了
Here we go, right, coming up to the Follow Through again. So slow.
转速提到6000转，又来了，我(和谐音)什么都看不见
Up to 6,000. And again,I can't see a BLEEP thing.
我很欣赏你的表现
This is, I really admire you for doing this.
带一点点刹车，没有贬低的意思。穿过轮胎墙
A touch of the brakes, and I can't say I blame you. Through the tyres.
没有抱怨。顺利通过倒数第二弯
No whingeing, no complaining.And, yeah, going to make that one.
不错，真的。这时刮来一阵狂风
Not bad at all, actually.And it's blowing a gale.
哇奥！这是吉米·卡尔的走法！就这样。冲线！
Whoa! It's the Jimmy Carr line!There we are. Across the line！
这真是，真的...从没看过这种表现
That is really, properly...I've never seen it like that.
是的，很刺激，因为最后一圈
Yeah, it was fascinating,because last time
同样很湿滑，基本上，不论你把我放到哪里
I came down it was wet as well, and basically, whenever you have me on,
毫无疑问的，这都是最湿滑的一圈，
詹姆仕·布朗特最湿滑的一圈
unsurprisingly, it is the wettest,James Blunt is the wettest lap.
前两周我们板子上已经有了两圈湿滑记录
We have had two previous wet laps in the last couple of weeks.
休·博内威利1分50秒1，
汤姆·希德斯顿上周做出了1分49秒9
Hugh Bonneville at 1.50.1,Tom Hiddleston last week at 1.49.9,
记住这点，他的圈速也很湿滑，但不像你这次...
so bearing in mind, he was very wet,but nothing like...
一点没我这圈湿滑。猜一下，你会在哪？
Not nearly as wet as me. So come on,where do you think you come?
我希望不要跑得太差
I really hope I haven't humiliated myself too much.
不，你跑的不差
No, you haven't humiliated yourself,
因为你开上了赛道，这已经很勇敢了，并且你成功完成了一圈
because you went out there, which is brave enough, and you drove around
表现很惊人，看起来你也信心十足
in it, which is very marvellous and you looked determined.
就像校运会，每个参与的人都是胜利者
Like one of those schools where everyone's a winner.
所以，目前最快湿圈，1分49.9秒。你的成绩...
So there we are, fastest lap so far,1.49.9. You did...
1分...
1...
49秒...
49...
4.
我要说...这是目前最快湿圈.你排在罗恩·霍华德前面
I have to say... That is the fastest wet lap. You are above Ron Howard.
就在乔丝·斯通的下面。
我一直在某些人的下面...好吧就这样
And just under Joss Stone.I'm always under some... Anyway
感觉背后有双眼睛正注视着我。是的。我能看见
Feel the eyes in the back of my head.Yes. I can see them.
你排在乔丝·斯通和罗恩·霍华德之间。真是个奇怪的排名
You're between Joss Stone and Ron Howard. That's a very odd place to be.
但真的很棒。确实如此。谢谢
That was quite something.It really was. Thank you.
女士们先生们，詹姆仕·布朗特！
Ladies and gentlemen, James Blunt!
谢谢
Thank you.
好的，今晚我们要证明我们确实喜欢小型车
Now, tonight we are trying to prove that we really do like small cars,
而制片人要证明它们是一堆垃圾
and our producers are trying to prove that they're rubbish.
是的，所以我们三被要求开着三辆1升排量的小掀背
Yes, so, they told us to drive our three one-litre hatchbacks
穿越乌克兰
all the way across Ukraine,
他们称这是一次地狱般的旅行
a trip they said would be the journey from hell.
他们为什么觉得这是一次地狱般的旅行？
Why do they think this is going to be the journey from hell?
开车横穿乌克兰
Driving across the Ukraine.
过去24小时里，我们经历了冷战，
We've only been here 24 hours,we've been through the Cold War
二战，克里米亚战争。让人印象深刻
the Second World War, the Crimean War. It's going to be tremendous.
就开着这辆Up！
And I'm in my Up!
在不久之前，我们驾驶的这些小型车
In the not too distant past,little cars like ours
还很简陋，但时至今日，如果你选则正确
were very spartan, but these days,if you choose your car wisely
你能得到一大堆有趣且实用的配置
you get loads of stuff to play with.
好的，哈蒙德，你的空调感觉如何？
Right, Hammond, have you got your air conditioning set just so?
是的，我刚刚把空调调低了半度
I have, yes, I've set it just half a degree lower
防止自己太舒适而睡着
than would be too comfortable.
这是座椅加热，我想设到一档就好
This heated seat, I think,just to the first position.
USB
USB.
USB iPod启动
USB iPod.'
蓝牙连接我的iPod到立体声音响
Bluetoothed my iPod into the stereo system.
车窗除雾，试试看
Heated windscreen, let me try that.
定速巡航。好像没用
Cruise control. Haven't done that.
很好，副驾有面镜子
Yep, a mirror on that side.
终于，我和哈蒙德把车上的所有功能都玩了个遍
Eventually, though, even Hammond and I ran out of things to play with,
于是我们把注意力都放到了欣赏乌克兰美景中去
so we turned our attention to the Ukrainian scenery.
放眼望去，空空如也
A hill or two wouldn't go amiss
好吧，我承认，这简直太无聊了
Right, I admit it, this is boring.
你们觉得行驶了有一半路程吗？
Do you think we're halfway there yet?
我们要弄清楚这个问题
We needed to find out.
于是，在看不懂卫星导航界面的情况下
So, as we couldn't understand the writing on our sat-nav systems,
我们靠边停车取出了地图
we pulled over to consult a map
我们从这里出发，对吧？
We came from down here, yes?
终点在这里
And we've got to go all the way there.
我们刚经过一个叫Pravda的小镇
We've just gone through a town called Pravda.
我们不可能离它有多远
We can't be further back than that.
可能在...不会是这。我们在这
Maybe it's in...Can't be there. We've done that
噢，老天，噢不！在这。别扯了！真的！我们才开到这！
Oh, Christ, oh no! It's there. Don't be daft! It is! We're only here!
我们才走了这么点距离。
只相当一个怀特岛的长度（英国南部海岛）。
We've only done that. We've only driven over the Isle of Wight.
我们要去这里。怎么能...我们才到这里？！
We've got to come here。How come ..We've only got there?!
这是个好消息。是么？
这怎么算是个好消息？确实是好消息
And that's good news. Is it? How is that good news? It's good news.
是么？是的
Really? Yes.
除了傻坐在车里大叫“真无聊”
Instead of just sitting and,"I'm bored,"
我们为什么不自己找点有意义的事情做呢？
why don't we make ourselves more rounded human beings on the journey?
你意思是我们在车里试着做点其他事？
So while we're in the car we learn to do some thing?
没错！我们可以在车里大叫“真无聊，真讨厌这次旅程”
Exactly! We could sit there going,
"I'm bored,I'm bored, I wish I wasn't doing this,"
也可以对自己说
“我要把这段时间利用起来干些有意义的事”
or we can simply say, "No, we shall use this time constructively.
我们能在抵达白俄罗斯之前
We will arrive in Belarus more intelligent
让自己过得更充实
and more rounded than we are now.
回到路上，我们的自我进修之旅开始了
Back on the road,the self-improvement began.
哈罗，欢迎来到乌克兰语自学课堂。第一讲
Hello and welcome to Teach Yourself Ukrainian. Unit one.
哈罗，你叫啥名？
Hello, what's your name?'
通过聆听这张CD你能快速学会
"You will learn to play blues harp quickly
如何吹奏蓝调口琴。
"and easily by just listening to the CD."
噢，这本书后面还有张CD！
Ooh, I've got a CD!And following the book."
各位亲，你们可能注意到了我正戴着一顶魔术帽
Viewers, you will notice I'm wearing my magic hat
并且有张纸牌贴在上面
and that there is a playing card in it.
Karus再次邀请Stephen到家中
Karus again invites Stephen to his home to discuss
讨论一些业务问题
some business questions.'
把它插进去
So that goes in there.
这...
Well...
在移动语言教室里，情况进展的不错
In the mobile language lab,things were going well.
内衣
Underwear.
很快我就有了在路边找家店
And soon I felt confident enough to get us
买点东西吃的信心
something to eat at a roadside cafe.
你在说啥？我说想买点非鱼类食物
What are you saying? I'm trying to find some food that isn't fish.
噢，谢谢
Oh, thank you.
好像你下了一比木材订单
You seem to have ordered some wood.
接着，杰瑞米想买些苹果
Jeremy then asked for some apples.
好吧，东西吃过了。能上路了吗？
Well, we've eaten. Shall we go?
第二天，在扔掉了多余的早餐之后...
The next morning, after breakfast had been cleared away..
何方暗器？！
What?!
我用新掌握的乌克兰语查看导航仪
I used my new Ukrainian skills to check the sat-nav.
噢，老天。离基辅还有13小时49分钟路程
Oh, Jesus. To get to Kiev,13 hours and 49 minutes.
正当我们绝望之际，在大雾弥漫中，穿过路边菜地
We were in a state of despair, but then, out of the fog loomed a man.
我们发现了这个
And behind him, this.
一片废弃的核弹发射基地
An abandoned nuclear missile base.
这是发射井，是吧？是的。很大啊
This is the silo, is it? That's a silo. It's ever so big
哈蒙德，这是一枚SS18洲际弹道导弹，北约代号“撒旦”，
打击目标是赫德福德郡的Ross-on-Wye镇
Hammond, this is an SS18, nicknamed the Satan, targeted Ross-on-Wye.
是吗？这上面写明了。等等。
Was it? That's what that says.Hang on a minute, though.
这上面写了“第二打击目标是Chipsky Norton”
It says "alternative target Chipsky Norton" there.
我猜它可能受潮了
I think it must be damp
很多人对长途驾驶有厌倦情绪，但这次旅途
Many people complain about having to do a long drive, but on this one,
被我们找到了让时间飞快流逝的办法
we really had hit on a brilliant way of making the time fly by.
哈哈！各位看官，我的手是空的
Ha ha! Viewers, my hands empty,
空无一物。现在，瞪大你的眼...
nothing at all in them.Now, can I...
第三单元。史蒂文，你有家人吗？又是史蒂文
'Unit three. Stephen, do you have a family?' There's Stephen again.
里面每个人都叫史蒂文，这是我学到的
Everybody's called Stephen here,that's the one thing I have learned.
噢，老天，我的鸽子逃出来了
Oh, God. My doves have escaped.
我的鸽子跑出来了。什么鸽子？
My doves have got out. What doves?
你啥意思？我的鸽子从魔术箱里跑出来了
What do you mean, got out? My doves from my magic box.
后备箱都是，到处便便
They're all over the back.They've crapped everywhere.
被鸽子骚扰一阵后，快崩溃的梅决定放走它们
Upset by the mess,OCD May ejected the culprit.
噢，老天，那卡车...那鸽子被处决了
Oh, my God, there's a lorry...That is an ex-dove.
是的，现在，你瞧那辆卡车撞上了你的鸽子，詹姆斯
Yeah, now, you see,the truck that hit your dove, James,
你的魔术学得怎么样了？说真的，它没飞走吗？
how good are you at magic? Seriously, did it not fly away?
你不会去参加小孩子的派对，对吧
You're not going to do children's parties, are you,
因为你可能要改变一下你的表演方式
because you're going to have to change your act if you are.
好吧，萨莉，这就是你家鹦鹉吗?
"So, Sally, is this the family parrot?
仔细看，当我把它扔出窗外的卡车时
"Just watch what happens
会发生什么奇迹
"when I throw it out of the window of a moving vehicle.
抛开这次意外的小悲剧
Putting this tragic incident behind us
我们继续前行，在夜色降临之前抵达了乌克兰首都，基辅
we ploughed on, and by nightfall had reached Ukraine's capital, Kiev.
杰瑞米带我们走进一家旅店
Jeremy checked us into the hotel
是的
Yeah.
你说yes是不是只想让他闭嘴？
Did you just say yes to stop him talking?
在酒吧里，詹姆斯表演了另一个失败魔术
And in the bar, James did another trick that went wrong.
哒-哒！
Ta-da!
我选的不是这张。你不能昧着良心说你之前挑的不是这张
I'm afraid not. You can't change your mind about the card you chose.
这就是你选的牌。你不能强行说这就是我选的牌
That was the card you chose.You can't tell me what card I chose.
但我知道你选的就是这张牌，因为我会读心术
But I know you chose that because I read your mind.
魔术师应该使用技巧征服观众，而不是靠耍流氓
Magicians are supposed to exercise a degree of finesse, not just bullying.
不，还是错的。就是它！这就是你选的
No, it's still not.It is! That's what you chose
第二天早上
The following morning,
我们被警告有一大群狂热粉丝在街上等着我们出现，事实确实如此
we were warned there was a mob on the streets of Kiev, and there was.
谢谢各位捧场，非常谢谢
Thank you for coming,thank you so much.
所以，为了获得短暂的宁静
So, to get a bit of peace and quiet,
我们被邀请体验当地唯一的一条赛道...
we were told to report to the country's only racetrack...
这也是本次的终极挑战
for what, chillingly,was called the final challenge.
你们每辆车都会加满23升的燃油
"Your cars will each be given exactly 23 litres of fuel,
考虑到它们都很省油
"which, because they're so economical,
所以这些油应该足够你们行驶100英里或更长
"should easily be enough for them to cover the 100 or so miles
以抵达本次挑战的目的地，一个白俄罗斯边境小镇
"to your destination, a town near the border with Belarus."
等等，23升？开100英里？
这根本就算不上是挑战，不是么？
Hang on, 23 litres? To do 100 miles? That's not really a challenge, is it?
简直太容易了！
你们的任务是在终点前耗光所有燃油。呃？
That's easy! "Your challenge is to run out before you get there." Eh?
你们绝对想达成这个目标
"This is something you will want to do,
因为终点小镇的名字叫...
"as the town in question is called...
切尔诺贝利
Chernobyl."
我们真的能...我们可以去那？能吗？
Can we actually...We can't go there, can we?
切尔诺贝利事件是人类历史上最严重的一次核事故
Chernobyl was the scene of the world's worst nuclear accident.
当1986年四号反应堆发生爆炸时，
When reactor number four exploded in 1986,
它向周围环境释放出大量放射性尘埃，
结果导致周围大片地区
it released a radioactive cloud so devastating that the entire area
在未来2万年内不再适宜人类居住
will remain uninhabitable for 20,000 years.
除非我们让各自车的耗油量保持在20英里每加仑以下
（超过百公里11.76升），
And unless we could make our cars do less than 20 miles to the gallon,
否则切尔诺贝利就是我们本次旅程的终点
this is where we'd end up.
福特称我的车每加仑能跑65英里（百公里3.6升）
Ford claim mine does 65mpg.
我这一路的油耗都在60英里每加仑（百公里3.9升）左右
All the way here, this has done 60 miles to the gallon, give or take.
是的。怎么可能让这些车做到20英里每加仑的耗油量？
Yes. How would you make these cars do 20 miles to the gallon?
我都不能想象它能降到30英里每加仑（百公里7.8升）
I can't imagine getting it under 30.
当制片人给每辆车精确加满23升燃油后
After the producers had put precisely 23 litres of fuel in each tank,
我们也在给各自车做着准备
we did some preparations of our own.
很好
Right.
我真是太TM机智了
Clever, this.
给每条轮胎放出30%气体
What I'm going to do is let about 30% of the pressure out of the tyres.
原理是这会增大滚动阻力
The point is,it increases rolling resistance
结果油耗能大大增加
which means I use more fuel.
增重完成
That is one heavy Up!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我把每条缝隙都用胶带密封防止放射性尘埃进入车内
I'm sealing all the gaps so that radioactive dust can't get in.
你这么干的结果就是，你让车身风阻更小了
What you've done there, Hammond is made it more aerodynamic.
是吗？是的。一路好走
I have, haven't I? You have. Goodbye.
为了让车在100英里内烧掉更多油
To get through this much petrol in less than 100 miles,
我们要像个神经病一样去开车才行
we would have to drive like maniacs.
3、2、1
Three, two, one.
上吧！拉高转速！
Come on! Build up the revs!
切二档。转速拉到红线区。老天，真浪费
Second gear. Right to the limiter.God, that's wasteful.
詹姆斯和我不约而同的想到了低档高转速耗油策略
James and I decided to go for a low-gear policy of maximum revs.
而另一边，哈蒙德...
Hammond, on the other hand...
如果我一路都这么开车，行驶里程就会变长
If I keep doing this all the way there, I'll go further.
这会让路程加倍。这就是解决之道。不停转向。喔哦！
It will be twice the distance. This is the answer. Lock to lock. Ooh!
这里要小心点
That's where I'm going to have to be careful,
这里交规靠右行
when there's traffic coming the other way.
才想起来！
I've just realised!
我居然没把灯组打开
I'm driving without the lights on.
还开着节能模式...
I'm driving with the eco-engine system...
后窗除雾开启，全部打开。座椅加热，是的
Heated rear window, I want that on.Heated seats, yes.
这就好多了
That's better.
看我这么开车别人会觉得我是个神经病
Probably people think this is a bit odd,
但如果他们知道我正在做什么的话，他们会理解的
but if they knew why I was doing it,they would understand.
简直不敢相信他们会让我们做这种事
I can't believe they're making us do this,
因为这个地区的辐射并没衰减。危害依旧存在
because it's not like the radioactivity has gone. It hasn t.
辐射物有半衰期，
那里残存的辐射污染物半衰期有24万5千年
It has a half-life, material that's left, of 245,000 years.
显然詹姆斯·梅，能解释什么是半衰期
And James May, obviously,can explain what a half-life is
实际上现在他很可能正滔滔不绝
In fact, he probably is doing.
半衰期几乎是恒定的。
A half-life is actually constant.
比如一块铀具有半衰期，当经过一个半衰期之后
A piece of uranium will have a half-life and when that half-life is passed,
剩余物质的半衰期依旧不变
the remaining bit still has the same half-life.
我认为这个词是由玛丽·居里首创的
I think the word was coined by Marie Curie.
在20世纪初
The early 20th century was the time
当放射现象首次被发现和定义时...
when radioactivity was identified and discovered...
经过25英里（40公里）的高转速路程后
After 25 miles of red-line motoring,
Up！的油耗依旧不容乐观
the news from the Up!still wasn't good.
我的平均油耗已经降到23英里每加仑（百公里10升）
I've managed to average 23 miles to the gallon.
必须更低。怎么能更低？
I've got to get that down.How do I get that down?
很好，现在空气阻力更大了
Right, the drag is now dramatically worsened.
与此同时...
Meanwhile...
说实在的，我有点想吐了
I am feeling a bit sick now,if I'm honest.
噢，那是警车？噢，老天
Oh, is that a police car? Oh, dear.
目前情况很糟
There's the horrible evidence.
已经跑了四分之一的路程，25.5英里（41公里）
At a quarter distance, 25.5 miles,
我应该消耗掉其中一格油量才对
I should have lost one of those four bars that I started with.
但油表连根毛都没变
But it's not happening.
快点啊，汽油！赶快烧完
Come on, petrol! Sod off.
OK，我们被警察拦住了
OK, we've been pulled by the police.
他们对我蛇形驾驶表示疑惑
They were wondering why I was zigzagging.
警察正和摄制组交谈
They're talking to the camera car in front.
与此同时，我让引擎疯狂空转
Meanwhile, I'm sitting here at max RPM to try and use some fuel
以便消耗更多燃油
while I'm stationary.
当哈蒙德还在骚扰警察时
Whilst Hammond was deafening the police,
我靠边停车拔掉了引擎管理系统控制线
I pulled over to disable my engine management system.
怎么样！
How about that!
发动机报警灯亮起。是的。就是我想要的
Engine warning light.Yes. That's what we want.
现在引擎启动了故障应急模式
What the engine has to do now is assume a sort of worst-case scenario,
因为它收不到传感器的各种数据
because it doesn't know anything about itself,
于是它认为现在温度很低，燃油品质很差
so it will assume it's very cold,the fuel quality is bad,
这样油耗就增大了
so it must be less efficient.
距切尔诺贝利还有30英里（48公里），
哥三的车依旧坚挺
30 miles from Chernobyl,all our cars were still running
我们尝试了已知的各种办法让车更耗油
and we were trying every trick in the book to make them conk out
看我现在的空气阻力！
Look at that for drag now!
刹车。加速
Brake. Then accelerate.
再刹车。在加速
Then brake. Accelerate.
还有三格油！老天！
Still got three bars! Come on!
看！17.8英里每加仑（百公里13.2升）。
我的油量报警灯亮了！噢，耶
There it is! 17.8mpg.My fuel light has come on! Oh, yeah.
21英里每加仑（百公里11.2升）。我做的还不够好！
I'm doing 21 miles to the gallon.I'm not doing well enough!
都空了。指针停在耗尽的位置
Everything's on empty.The needle, on empty.
快点，停下来。停住
Come on, run out. Run out.
车外气温只有一摄氏度。都快冻僵了
It's one degree out there.Nipples are sticking out badly.
啊！我看见理查德·哈蒙德了
Ah! I believe this is Richard Hammond.
这车应该停下来了
This thing should not be moving
我做到了！我做到了！我做到了！
别告诉我你已经把油烧完了。没错！
I'm going! I'm going! I am going!Don't tell me you've run out. Yes!
是的！哈！哈！噢，太爽了！停下来了
Yes! Ha ha! Oh, bliss! It's gone
简直不敢相信。它...
I don't believe you. It...
你难以置信。下一讲
I don't believe you. Sit rep.
理查德·哈蒙德是个（和谐音）
Richard Hammond is a BLEEP.
你继续。向地狱前进
Go on. Go and meet your fate.
没有涡轮的Up！继续前行。直到...
The un-turbo-charged Up! continued onwards. And then...
噢，等等。那是啥？好象是个检查站
Oh, wait a minute. What do we have here? Some kind of checkpoint
辐射区周围30英里（48公里）被隔离起来
The barrier marked the start of the 30km exclusion zone,
现在我不得不进入辐射区了。詹姆斯也一样
and now I'd have to go through it.So would James.
但进去之后谁来摄像？
But who would film what happened afterwards?
摄制组的三个摄像师。是的
Three main cameramen. Yeah.
他们打道回基辅了。什么？
They're getting in a taxi and going back to Kiev. What?
他们不打算进去。就这么闪人了
They're not going in。There they go
所以我们即将进入全世界最危险的地方，和两个...
So we film the most dangerou thing we ever done with two...
我无意冒犯，但只是两个摄影助理而已
I don’t want be rude。But camera assists
我要感谢你们。是的
I actually want thank you.yes.
感谢你们，你们非常勇敢
Thank you very much，you are very brave
现在你们晋升为官方摄像师了
You are now promote the official cameramen.
我知道你们现在很想马上逃走，但...这次挑战意义重大
I know you want to get out on the road,
but this is... this is a bit much
这是我们为进入隔离区所做的准备工作
Those was us all going in made that preparations
好的，切换内循环，出风口关闭
Right，air on recycle,vents shut
盖革计数器。开启
Geiger counter.on
这是台货真价实的盖革计数器。一直在嗒嗒作响
That really is a Geiger counter.and its really going tick-tick
摄影师像往常一样在揽胜后面进行拍摄，
但是车门是关上的
The cameramen has to film at back with landrover as usual，
but with the door closed
通常后门是开启的
normal the tailgate is proper open
目前仍有17吨左右高放射性废料
There's something like 17 tonnes of radioactive waste
暴露在核心反应区
still in the exposed reactor core.
苏联人在核心外围建造了一座巨大的石棺
They're building an enormous sort of arch, really, over
罩住整个反应堆，防止污染扩散，但没彻底完工
the entire site, which will seal it off, but that is not finished yet.
距离8公里，我开始祈求上帝
With 8km to go,I had started to beg.
耗光、赶快耗光
Run out. Run out now.
但啥事也没发生
But it didn't.
辐射仪指针一直在升高
That needle is definitely moving.
迹象很明显，我们已经不可避免地
Now it had become imperative we didn't run out
要经过核心辐射区了
until we were well past the reactor.
就是它
There it is.
那就是四号主反应堆的真身
That is the remains of reactor number four.
难以置信
This is unbelievable.
我知道现在不是为这事得意的时候
I wouldn't want to appear to be gloating at a time like this,
但我车还有两格油量
but I do still have two bars of fuel left.
但我没有
I didn't.
噢，天啊！别现在停下
Oh, my God! Don't stop now.
像往常一样，我遇到了大麻烦
And as a result,I was in serious trouble.
这里就是当年核电厂职工的生活区
This is where the people who worked at the nuclear facility all lived.
被彻底遗弃。已经过去28年了
Totally abandoned now.It has been for 28 years.
看呐。瞧那边
Look at it. Look at that there.
这应该是世上最令人震撼的场景了
This has to be one of the world's most astonishing spectacles.
噢，我的天...我见过这场景！
Oh, my... I've seen this!
就是这。这就是传说中的游乐场
This is it. This is the playground.
哇噢，惊人的辐射量。确实要离开这了
Whoa, big spike. It is definitely now time to get out of here.
挺住，Up！别在这里停下
Come on, little Up!Don't run out now.
噢，这...它没油了
Oh, that was... It coughed.
没油了。没油了。它不动了
That was a cough.It's gone. It's gone.
大家为啥鼓掌？有啥好鼓掌的？
Why are they applauding that? Why are you applauding?
最后你咋离开那的？
So how did you get out?
我就在那等着，猜测你会回头来救我，但你却...
I waited, thinking you would come and rescue me, which you...
好吧，我没有，因为...你没回来
Well, I didn't, because...No, you didn't.
因为那时我想，
我们需要留一人在那座荒芜的城市里自生自灭
We do leave a man in the field, or in this case, the contaminated city.
没错，所以我只好走着出来。
真的？现在有啥感觉吗？是的
Yes, so I had to walk. Really? So, any effects? Yes.
我和两个没义气的混球录了整整一小时的节目
I've had to present this entire show with two penises.
并且这种脑残事我坚持干了11年
But then, I have been doing that for 11 years.
说得好
Funny.
不论如何，说回到车，最关键的部分
Anyway, right, the cars,the important bit.
是的，嘉年华太棒了。是的，我知道。它救了我的命
Yes, and the Fiesta is brilliant.Yes, I know it is. It saved my life.
是的，它做到了
Yes, it did.
没错，但要明白，达契亚，
哈蒙德，比你的车便宜1万英镑（101476人民币）
Yes, but we must remember, the Dacia, Hammond, is £10,000 cheaper.
是啊，因为它是台垃圾
Yes, because it's rubbish.
不，如果你要买一辆小车，你最关注的是价格
No, but if you buy a small car,you want it to be cheap.
不，品质才是最重要的。实际上，两样都重要
No, you want it to be good.Actually, you want it to be both.
是啊，但Up！两样都缺
Yes, but the Up! is neither.
听着，梅，你曾亲口说过Up！非常优秀
Listen, May, you said the Up!was brilliant and intelligent.
我啥时候说过这话？
When did I say that?
18个月前你在一本杂志上写过一篇这样的测评文章
You wrote it in a road test in a magazine about 18 months ago.
真希望你没看见过那篇测评
I was rather hoping you wouldn't have read that.
是的，但我看过了
Yes, but I did read it.
所以，这次节目再次证明
So once again, it turns out that on this show,
我的观点是最客观和理性的。是吗？
I am the voice of reason and common sense. Really?
没错，Up！是最值得购买的小车
Yes, and the Up!Is the small car to buy.
但不是这辆，这辆被辐射过了
Not that one, though, because that's been irradiated.
是啊，但是，哈蒙德，你还敢坐在它上面
Yes, actually, Hammond,you are sitting on it,
也就说你现在患上了辐射PP病
which means you now have a radioactive anus.
啊！
Ah!
伴着这条爆炸性新闻，是时候说再见了。感谢各位的观看
And on that bum-shell, it's time to end. Thank you so much for watching.
我们下周见。晚安
See you next week. Good night.
遗忘天下，个人翻译，如有错误，万望海涵
译制：遗忘天下 后期校订：遗忘天下 上传：遗忘天下
QQ号：529098103 欢迎车迷同学加好友
英文字幕来源http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.